export const riskQuestions = [
  {
    question: "Question 1",
    text: "Mrs. Summers just turned age 65. She is eligible for Social Security coverage. Which of the following is true?",
    options: [
      "A. If she applies at age 65 for Medicare Part A and Part B, she is automatically covered.",
      "B. If she applies at age 65 for Medicare Part A only, she can never apply for Part B later.",
      "C. If she declines coverage at age 65, she can never apply for Medicare Part A or B later.",
      "D. If she applies for Part B at a later date (after age 65), the coverage is automatic, and the premium is the same as age 65.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    explanation:
      "Anyone who fails to enroll during the initial enrollment period may enroll during a general enrollment period (each year from 1/1 to 3/1). Coverage begins next July. The premium will be high (10% for each 12 month period late).",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 2",
    text: `Paul has an incurable disease and a maximum life expectancy of 2 years. He would like to live out his remaining days seeing the world. He has a life insurance policy with a death benefit of $500,000 and $40,000 of cash value. A viatical settlement company offers him $325,000 in cash. If he sells the policy and the viatical company pays 8 more premiums of $4,000 each before Paul dies, which of the following is true?
I. The $325,000 paid to Paul is received tax-free.
II. $285,000 ($325,000 paid less $40,000 cash value) is taxable to Paul.
III. The $500,000 death benefit is tax-free to the viatical company.
IV. $357,000 of the death benefit is tax-free to the viatical company.`,
    options: ["A. I, III", "B. I, IV", "C. II, III", "D. II, IV"],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "When the $500,000 is paid as a death benefit to the viatical company, the company's basis in the policy is $357,000 ($325,000 + 32,000). The $32,000 is 8 payments of $4,000. The difference of $143,000 is taxed as ordinary income to the viatical company.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 3",
    text: `Under Section II of the homeowners policy, which of the following is/are specific exclusions under the personal
liability section?
I. Liability arising from business activities
II. Liability arising out of usage of aircraft
III. Liability arising out of usage of motorized land vehicles off property
IV. Intentional loss`,
    options: ["A. All of the above", "B. I, II", "C. III, IV", "D. IV"],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    explanation: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 4",
    text: "Martha has a noncan own occ disability insurance policy that has a guaranteed insurability option. She recently received a raise from $60,000 annually to $6,000 per month. She believes that her standard of living will go up. She wants to increase her disability coverage to protect her. She wants to increase it from 60% to 85% of lost wages. She had a heart attack two years ago and found she struggled on 60% of her salary. She doesn't want that to happen again. If she tries to increase the policy to her desired limits, what will likely occur?",
    options: [
      "A. The insurance company will not provide the additional coverage because of her health history.",
      "B. The insurance company will not provide the additional coverage up to 85% because the limit is too high.",
      "C. The insurance company has to provide the additional coverage up to 85% because she has a guaranteed insurability option.",
      "D. The insurance company does not have to provide the additional coverage because it has the option to guarantee additional coverage.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "The maximum percentage of salary any carrier will issue is about 60%. 85% is impossible. The carrier will issue an additional 60% of $12,000 ($72,000 new income less $60,000 of old income).",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 5",
    text: "Which one of the following describes the conversion provision in a life insurance policy?",
    options: [
      "A. The insured may exchange a term insurance policy (ART) for a 30-year level term policy without proof of insurability.",
      "B. The insured may exchange term insurance for permanent insurance without having to show evidence of insurability.",
      "C. The insured may exchange permanent insurance for term insurance without proof of insurability.",
      "D. The insured is guaranteed the right to exchange term insurance for permanent insurance only if he or she becomes disabled.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "The patient is responsible for the first 3 units of blood. Eye care is not covered. Skilled care is limited to 100 days.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 6",
    text: "Which of the following does Medicare (A, B & D) cover?",
    options: [
      "A. First 3 units of blood in a calendar year",
      "B. Eye care",
      "C. Drugs for hospice enrollees",
      "D. Skilled nursing home care over 100 days at 100%",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "It is important to remember you can only exchange term for permanent.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 7",
    text: `Which of the following describes a modified endowment contract?
I. Meets the requirements of a life insurance contract
II. Was entered into on or after June 21, 1988
III. Fails to meet the "seven pay test"
IV. Meets the guideline premium and corridor test or cash value accumulation test`,
    options: [
      "A. I, IV",
      "B. II, III",
      "C. I, II, III",
      "D. II, III, IV",
      "E. I, II, III, IV",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 4,
    explanation:
      "I through IV are all elements of the IRC definition of a modified endowment contract.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 8",
    text: `Whole life insurance has policy provisions or riders for which of the following options?
I. Guaranteed insurability option
II. Non-forfeiture options
III. Dividend options
IV. Settlement options`,
    options: ["A. All of the above", "B. I, III", "C. II, IV", "D. III"],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    explanation: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 9",
    text: "Lilly Thomas just bought a long-term care insurance policy. At age 79, with some existing health issues the policy was rated up (extra premium). She used a 6 month wait with maximum benefits for 4 years. The premium was $5,000 per month. Lilly files a 1040 with a Schedule A. How much of the $5,000/mo is a deduction subject to 71⁄2% of AGI?",
    options: [
      "A. The question is written incorrectly. It is subject to 10% AGI.",
      "B. The deduction is subject to a dollar amount limitation based on age.",
      "C. Because the policy is rated, it is impossible to arrive at a based premium dollar amount.",
      "D. Why would someone pay $60,000 a year for long-term care insurance?",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "This is a definition answer. Since she is over 65, the 71⁄2% rule still applies this year. Answer C is nonsense. Answer D does not answer the question.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 10",
    text: "Can a minor purchase a life insurance policy?",
    options: [
      "A. No, why would a minor need life insurance?",
      "B. No, life carriers have a minimum age requirement.",
      "C. Yes, a minor can purchase a life insurance policy if an adult (normally a parent) applies as owner.",
      "D. Yes, a minor can purchase a life insurance policy if he/she has enough earned income to qualify.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation: "The owner must have legal capacity to execute contracts.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 11",
    text: "Tom Allen is considering purchasing either a whole life or a variable universal life policy. What could be a factor for him to choose?",
    options: [
      "A. He would have to pay premiums until age 100.",
      "B. He has a high-risk tolerance.",
      "C. He will have a cash value he can borrow from should he need money.",
      "D. He has guaranteed premiums until age 100.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "With a variable contract, he can invest the separate account in the market (high risk tolerance). With VUL or WL, he would have to pay premiums until age 100, and both would have a cash value he could borrow from no significant difference. In VUL, depending on the contract, his premiums might be guaranteed.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 12",
    text: "Tim Brown's home was heavily damaged by fire. He is forced to temporarily live in a hotel and eat all his meals out. His normal monthly living expenses were $2,500. Due to his situation, his living expenses are now $4,000. If his loss of use coverage (Coverage D) is $50,000, how much will the insurance carrier reimburse him each month?",
    options: ["A. $1,500", "B. $2,500", "C. $4,000", "D. $5,000 for 10 months"],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    explanation:
      "Coverage only pays for the necessary increase in living expense (the difference between $4,000 and $2,500).",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 13",
    text: "A little over a year ago Len Harris purchased a variable annuity for $100,000. Recently, due to bad investment choices, the value of the annuity fell to $90,000. Len has decided to liquidate the annuity. Which of the following is true?",
    options: [
      "A. He will receive $100,000. The annuity cannot be worth less than $100,000.",
      "B. His loss of $10,000 is not deductible.",
      "C. His loss of $10,000 is a capital loss.",
      "D. His loss of $10,000 is an ordinary loss.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    explanation:
      "Surrender of annuities are subject to ordinary gains or losses.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 14",
    text: "Patricia buys a whole life policy. She pays the normal level premium. Which of the following is not true?",
    options: [
      "A. She can borrow money from the contract tax-free.",
      "B. If she borrows money from the contract, the loan interest is personal interest and is not deductible.",
      "C. If she dies, the death proceeds are income tax free.",
      "D. If she surrenders the contract, the cash value paid to her will be tax-free",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    explanation:
      "Answer D is not always true. If the policy has a gain above basis, the gain is ordinary income. Interest on policy loans is no longer deductible.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 15",
    text: "Tom lives out in the country. Through a neighbor's land, he has access to a lake for his boat. His neighbor builds a house on the land and a high wooden fence around the land. Tom burns some trash near the fence and catches the fence on fire. Because the neighbor's fence is attached to the neighbor's house, the house catches on fire. Tom does nothing to stop the fire even though the neighbor is away. If the neighbor sues Tom, will Tom's umbrella policy cover the damage?",
    options: [
      "A. Only if Tom maintains the required underlying coverage for his homeowners",
      "B. Yes, if the claim is made",
      "C. No, because it does not cover property owned by the insured",
      "D. No",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    explanation:
      "This sounds like an act committed with the intent to cause property damage.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 16",
    text: `ACV stands for which of the following?`,
    options: [
      "A. At Current Value",
      "B. Actual Cash Value",
      "C. Assumed Current Valuation",
      "D. Actual Certified Value",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "ACV losses are settled by the formula of replacement cost less depreciation.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 17",
    text: "Which of the following types of specific information should not be gathered in the planning process in regards to the client's life insurance contracts?",
    options: [
      "A. Premium and dividend options",
      "B. Property insured",
      "C. Policy loans",
      "D. Ownership",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation: "The question is asking about life insurance.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 18",
    text: `Toby Smith, age 65, bought a whole life policy some years ago. He decides to surrender the policy . The current
values are the following.
Cash value                             $50,000
Premiums billed                        $35,000
Existing loan                          $30,000
Dividend reducing premium              $15,000
How much of the surrender value will be subject to income tax?`,
    options: ["A. $15,000", "B. $20,000", "C. $30,000", "D. $35,000"],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation: `Cash value less basis $50,000 - 20,000* = $30,000
*Basis is $35,000 billed - 15,000 dividends = $20,000`,
  },
  {
    question: "Question 19",
    text: `Whole life has a contract provision called APL. What is APL?`,
    options: [
      "A. Applicable premium loan",
      "B. Automatic premium loan",
      "C. Accumulate paid-up life",
      "D. Accelerated premium leverage",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "If APL is elected paid and the policyholder does not pay the premium during the grace period, the company will automatically pay the premium and charge it against the cash value of the policy (make a loan).",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 20",
    text: `Bob and Jane Byrd live in Florida. They recently bought land in the North Carolina foothills. What do you suggest they do with the land in North Carolina?`,
    options: [
      "A. Sell it as real estate is going bust",
      "B. Nothing until they build on it",
      "C. Extend liability protection from their existing homeowner policy and umbrella policy to the land",
      "D. Buy an umbrella policy for the land",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "Answer C is better than Answer D. For one it will probably be less expensive. Secondly, for the umbrella to work properly, the underlying protection afforded by the homeowners does not exist in Answer D.",
  },
];
